KELECHI WHITNEY ADIUKU

Product Management | Project Management | IT Management Lekki Lagos || adiukukelechi@gmail.com || +234 816 6821804 || linkedin.com/in/kelechi-adiuku

CAREER PROFILE

An attitude of determination to finding solutions to challenges with the goal of making valuable contributions in teamwork and a commitment to learning. Sound knowledge and competency of Software Development Life Cycle methodologies (SDLC) with programming experience in different languages, knowledge of different technical stacks, knowledge of Project Management, Business Analysis, Business Intelligence and Business development. Proven experience building effective relationships across matrix organizations at the working level and with the C-suite. Known ability to deliver success in the transformation of organizations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web design and development.
- Requirements analysis, software development and installation, database design and implementation, integration, evaluation, enhancement, maintenance, testing, project management, and problem diagnosis and resolution.
- Finding and fixing software bugs in existing code.
- Software test, design, analysis, and test result analysis and reporting.
- Working with little direction toward predetermined long-range goals and objectives.
- Proven to work unusually complex technical problems and provide solutions which are innovative and ingenious.

Operating Systems: Windows and Android OS

Programming: HTML, CSS, Jquery, JavaScript, PHP, Python, Django, HTML, SQL, Google Web Toolkit and more

API Knowledge: REST, SOAP

Database Systems: MySQL, MS SQL Server, sql

Applications: Photoshop, Github, CI/CD, WordPress, Open Cart, Hootsuite, Wix, Canva, Trello and Teamwork, Yoast SEO, Beaver

Builder, Gravity Forms, Advanced Custom Fields and more

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT MANAGER / PROJECT MANAGER

Nov 2020 - Date

Farmforte - Freshforte

Farmforte is an impact-oriented value chain development firm focused on creating novel solutions to existing problems in the African agriculture landscape and transforming them to economic opportunities.

- Train staff on inventory tracking software (EPOS).
- Monitor performance of EPOS systems to determine cost, loss and productivity levels, and to make recommendations for improving the software.
- Design, develop, implement and coordinate system processes in all location areas (restaurant, supermarket, cafe/juice bar, backend office).
- Troubleshoot hardware and software issues.
- Preserve assets, information security and control structures.
- Provide project updates on a consistent basis to various stakeholders about strategy, adjustments, and progress to executive management
- Manage contracts with vendors and suppliers by assigning tasks and communicating expected deliverables
- Participating in tender process i.e. design, submission and review
- Managing the development team building the risk management software (Audit- trail).

NaCareers Limited

NgCareers is a career and learning development company that serves businesses and customers with diverse career solutions including job databases and learning platforms.

- Led the development efforts of the reengineered NgCareers platform for Businesses that wanted to advertise job roles and candidates that applied for such roles. This increased site traffic and expanded the user base from 350,000 users to over 1,000,000 users with over 50,000 Daily Active Users.
- Responsible for the technical analysis and design of "Lentora", an e-learning platform, this new product unlocked revenue of about \$100,000 just in the first three months of the product launch.
- Collaborated with 7 different teams for the delivery of both products.
- Managed stakeholder expectations for the products while ensuring the product features were clear and well defined.
- Ensured all software activities were conducted in accordance with the Software Development Life Cycle.
- Adhered to code ethics by refactoring existing code to improve code quality.
- Mentored and challenged team members to develop better code and improve quality.

SEO & CONTENT ANALYST Mar 2018 – Jan 2019

Shopflex Limited, UK (Remote)

- Managed Content Writers and ensured all content were readable, concise, and clear to rank in Google and Bing ratings, significantly increased product ratings across the platform by more than 90%.
- Optimized SEO for products and blog content for niche stores, increasing revenue for the stores per click conversions by 70% aggregated across all the stores.
- Oversaw the development of product campaign assets including social media and packaging for online presence and branding.
- Trained staff on social media and content management, using WebEx and Skype.
- Managed the inventory of the chain stores on Amazon, ensuring visibility and high turnover. Had a successful conversion rate of one click to five viewed products.
- Managed manufacturers from china to ensure timely production and shipment to warehouses.

PROJECT MANAGER May 2017 – Mar 2018

Ash Nelson Partners

A SaaS based company that delivers software products and services to a variety of Businesses and Organizations in the Fintech and Social Media space

- Worked with my team to develop a multi-tenancy product worth over \$2 Million.
- Planned and coordinated project schedules, goals, and milestones for all developers (using teamwork).
- Presented and sent out reports on progress of the project to all stakeholders involved.
- Worked within the budget provided and ensured the goals and milestones were met and the so=cope was adhered to.
- Designed product process flows across each tenancy to develop technical architecture to enable back end developers achieve product goals.
- Created functional specification and requirement documentations to aid team develop the right features for business solutions.
- Identified innovative features and front-end performance that optimized the solution for ease and adoption, when used by customers.
- Attended meetings with top management for further enlightenment of the proffered technical solution.

TECHNICAL ANALYST Oct 2015 – May 2017

Bord Innovant International Limited

Bord Innovant International Limited is an IT firm that provides services like consultancy, web, and application development. Bord Innovant is a parent company of The Naira Shop an online marketplace

Duties

- Participated in the development automation of various projects including Limi Hospital and Lawcas Pharmacy.
- Assisted and identified required product modifications and enhancements by carrying out surveys with feedback from the
 merchants and customers, translating the results of the surveys into features.
- Participating in the development efforts to build functionalities that improved the platforms, successfully giving them a
 more user-friendly environment.

- Planned and estimated development tasks and worked to improve performance metrics.
- Worked closely with other senior engineers to develop the best technical designs and approach for new product development.
- Took complete ownership of development work assigned.
- Monitored and tracked industry demands and competitor enhancements to improve product performance.
- Built trust-based relationships with merchants and customers.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Web programming with Python and JavaScript

2021

Harvard University (EdX)

In view

B.Sc Computer Science 2010-2014

Bingham University